我不記得家里有買新鮮的蜜桃小翹臀啊
I don't remember buying these fresh peaches.
抱歉 瑟奇
Apologies, Serge.
我妻子克萊爾似乎忘記了
My wife, Claire, seems to have forgotten
我在家里辦公
that I'm holding office hours
讓房地產入門課的學生來學習
for my Intro to Real Estate class here at home.
所以我十分鐘前
So, when I walked to the laundry room
只穿著文胸進洗衣房時...
10 minutes ago in my bra...
時機倒是再合適不過了
That was kind of perfect, actually.
我剛給他講完 七十年代早期的"建筑"
I had just made a point about how buildings from the early '70s
至今仍出人意料地"堅挺"
were holding up surprisingly well.
或許我該...
So maybe I'll...
-是啊 -是啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
上課時見 伙計
All right, see you in class, buddy.
多好的孩子
What a great kid.
這就是我獻身學術界的原因 克萊爾
That's why I chucked it all for a life in academia, Claire.
這感覺太特別了
It's a special feeling
知道這世界某處有個年輕人
knowing that there's a young man walking around out there
是你幫忙打造他的品格 能讓你驕傲
who you helped mold, who you can be proud of.
-爸 -你懂嗎
- Hey, Dad. - Hey. You know?
你起得真早
You're up early.
你這話什么意思
What are you talking about?
剛才我還從背后抱你來著
I hugged you from behind earlier.
我說"我不記得家里有買六塊腹肌[啤酒]啊"
You know, I said, "I don't remember buying this six pack."
然后你用很搞笑的東歐口音說
Then you did that funny Eastern European accent --
"我不想惹麻煩
"I don't want trouble.
我只想學習"
I just want to learn."
我們是否該擔憂一下集體性騷擾瑟奇的事
Should we be concerned about group-molesting Serge?
而且你不是再少一個學生
And aren't you at the minimum number of students
-課程就會被取消嗎 -不必擔心
- before they cancel your class? - Not to worry.
瑟奇很崇拜我 班上其余同學也很靠譜
Serge worships me, and the rest of the class is super solid.
再說 過了今天就不準棄課了
Plus, it's the last day to drop classes anyway.
說到棄課
Oh, speaking of that,
我在考慮放棄歷史課
I'm thinking about dropping history.
-為什么 -我覺得很無趣
- How come? - It's not really exciting me.
再說 有份大論文今天該交
Plus, we've got this huge paper due today
我的開始動工計劃還沒結束
that I haven't quite finished starting.
要寫門羅主義
It's on the Monroe Doctrine.
門羅主義
The Monroe Doctrine?
糟糕
Oh, no.
大三歷史課
Junior year history class,
我寫了一份完美的論文
I wrote the perfect paper.
強力的論點 無可挑剔的輔助論證
Strong thesis, impeccable supporting arguments.
我引用了一位白宮侍從的信件
I quoted from the letters of a White House footman
他回憶道 門羅在浴缸中叫他
who recalled Monroe calling to him from the bath,
"博勒加德 把我的馬褲給我
"Beauregard, fetch me my breeches.
我想到了一個主義"
We have a doctrine!"
我只得了C
I got a "C."
你認為這成績合理是嗎
Oh, so you agree with that grade, huh?
別把我當小孩哄
Don't patronize me.
俱樂部的飲食變得清淡健康多了
The food at the club has gotten so much lighter and healthier.
好幾個人心絞痛連續發作
We had a run of angina attacks,
所以我們不得不重視心臟健康
so we had to go heart-healthy.
我們在同一個周末先后失去了
We said goodbye to our social chairman, Herb,
社交主席賀布和黃油噴泉
and our butter fountain in the same weekend.
我很遺憾
Oh, I'm sorry.
普里契特先生
Hey, Mr. Pritchett.
您隨時可以結賬了
I'll take this when you're ready.
-謝謝你 瑪利亞 -瑪利亞
- Thank you, Maria. - Oh, Maria,
很美的名字 所以常被歌唱
that's a beautiful name. That's why it's often sung.
但你不會唱的
But you're not going to --
?萬福瑪利亞?
♪ Ave Maria ♪
謝幕 行了 他們剛允許同性戀進門
And curtain. Okay, they just started letting gays in here.
別讓他們后悔
Don't make them regret it.
你或許也該告訴夏羅娜[歌名]
You might also wanna tell Sharona
-不要靠近這張桌子 -沒錯
- to steer clear of the table. - Yes.
反正我或許也該留著精力
Yeah, well, I should probably save my energy
為今晚的演出做準備
for my performance tonight anyway.
見鬼 歌洛莉亞和我買了票要去看...
Oh, darn. Gloria and I have tickets to, um...
別擔心 杰 不用你去看
Don't worry, Jay. It's-it's not for you.
太好了 我還真編不下去了
Oh, good. I didn't know where I was going with that.
今晚是莉莉學校的募捐演出
Tonight is a fundraiser at Lily's school.
我們在為孩子們募捐
We're, you know, raising money for the kids.
歌唱與小品之夜
A night of song and sketch.
所有孩子爸爸都要演出 或者說
All the dads are performing. Well...
大多數爸爸
most of the dads.
為你驕傲 兒子
Proud of you, son.
我也不是徹底的勝利
Ah, it's not a complete victory.
我還是得去看的
I still have to watch it, so...
多謝你請客吃早飯 爸
Thanks for breakfast, Dad.
我喜歡和你們倆共度時光
I love spending time with you two!
我每個月在俱樂部有最低消費
Every month I've gotta burn off a minimum at the club,
而我認識的每個人居然都沒空
and literally, everybody else I knew was busy.
這也是為什么我送出的好多生日禮物
That's also why I give a lot of birthday presents
都是俱樂部專賣店買的 馬克杯
from the pro-shop. You know, mugs
遮陽帽 上面印著"跟我的推桿說去"
and visors that say "Kiss My Putter,"
"挑逗我 小鳥球"
"Talk Birdie To Me."
都是好產品 雙贏
Quality items. Everybody wins.
假如你們不著急的話
So, if you're not rushed,
該去我們的水療享受一下
you should treat yourself to our spa.
去試試看...
You know, get a couple of, uh...
標準按摩套餐
a couple of standard treatments.
你真慷慨
Oh, well, you're so generous.
我想說 我們圣誕時送你的這件襯衫
Might I say you look very handsome
你穿著十分精神
in that shirt we gave you for Christmas.
這款還有"皇后珊瑚粉" 糟糕
They also make it in "Queen's coral" -- oh, no.
我是不是劇透了你的生日禮物
Did I spoil your birthday?
聽起來是的
Sounds like you might.
-什么事這么好笑 -不過是
- What's so funny? - Oh, it's just that
我和學校的一個孩子媽互通電郵
I've been e-mailing this mom at school.
我和她一起做志愿者
We both volunteer together.
-你發電郵 -沒什么的 聽著
- You-you e-mail? - It's harmless. Listen.
"杰 在天文館和你說笑很開心
"Hey, Jay, enjoyed laughing around the planetarium with you.
你的笑話能把人笑到天外"
Your jokes were out of this world."
好吧 假如沒有什么
Hm, okay. So, if it's so harmless,
歌洛莉亞肯定也知道這位妙語撩騷的女士
I'm sure Gloria knows about this flirty quipstress.
別添油加醋
Don't make something out of this.
我的天
Oh, my God.
所以他才穿了這件襯衫
That's why he's wearing the shirt.
因為它能襯托出你的藍眼睛
Because it makes your blue eyes pop.
我不會讓你們倆八婆把這潭水弄渾
I'm not letting you magpies dirty this up.
"把車停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好幫你把東西拿進來"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
"把車停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好幫你把東西拿"進"來"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
你們這是抹黑 我走了
You're sullying this, and I'm leaving!
-向你女朋友帶好 -她不是我女朋友
- Okay, well, say "Hi" to your girlfriend. - She's not my girlfriend.
我們倆會配成一組的唯一理由
The only reason we're paired together
就是因為我們的孩子在同一個閱讀小組
is because our kids are in the same reading group.
去你們的
Damn it!
我太喜歡我們的"哦喲喲"了
I love when we "Ooh."
以前我們經常這樣 后來不了
We used to do that all the time, and then we stopped.
-為什么 -我不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
喬
Joe!
為什么我在垃圾桶里
Why did I find your eye patch
-發現了你的眼罩 -我不知道
- in the garbage? - I don't know.
因為你又去扔了一張停車罰單嗎
Were you throwing away another parking ticket?
你必須戴上
Okay, you have to put it on.
為什么 我的弱視已經好了
Why? My lazy eye is fixed.
好啦 有我在呢
Okay, I'm over here,
再堅持一周
and it's only one more week.
你看起來很硬漢
And you look tough,
像個小戰神
like a little warlord.
利亞姆的媽媽到了
Oh, that's Liam's mom.
放學見
See you after school.
好的寶貝 不過答應我
Okay, papi, but promise me
你一整天都會乖乖
that you're going to wear the eye patch
-戴眼罩 -我會戴的
- the whole day. - I will.
真不敢相信你不信任我
I can't believe you don't trust me.
兩天前
Two days ago,
我抓到你想
I caught you trying to copy
用打印機復印20美元
a $20 bill in the printer.
爸爸說等我能自己賺錢[造錢]的時候
Dad says I get to pick what we watch on TV
我就能決定我們看什么節目
when I start making my own money.
上學去吧
Go to school.
要是你們準備好了
If you guys are ready,
我和胡里奧就開始了
me and Julio will get started.
對了 你們是不是在校園操場遇到的呢
Oh, by any chance, did you guys meet down by the schoolyard?
-? 我 ? -別 別 好了
- ♪ Me ♪ - No -- No. Okay.
就是這里
Oh, that's the spot.
現在我想起來為什么我們
Now I'm remembering why we haven't had
蜜月之后就沒有一起做過按摩了
a couples massage since our honeymoon.
阿魯巴[阿魯巴島]
Aruba.
那不是我們度蜜月的地方
That's not where we went.
那是他發出的噪音
That's the noise he made.
阿 魯 巴
Arrruuuubaaaa.
小卡 你能稍微
Cam, could you just...
稍微 噓
just...shh.
-抱歉 -謝謝
- I'm sorry. - Thank you.
好了 夠了 我今天就到這了
Okay, you know what? I'm gonna call it.
-不做了 -怎么了 他太過火了嗎
- Mm-hmm. Nope. - What happened? Was he forward?
不是 我只是無法
No, I just can't relax
在你發出那些聲音的時候放松下來
with you making these noises.
那我不發出那些聲音就放松不下來
Well, I can't relax without making the noises.
所以我要走了 謝謝你 胡里奧
Which is why I'm leaving. Thank you, Julio,
不好意思 我沒記住你的名字
and I'm sorry. I-I didn't catch your name.
我叫啊喂嗎喂
It's A-weema-weh.
祝你們倆好運
Good luck to you both. Okay.
盧克 親愛的
Oh, Luke! Honey, hi.
你好啊 媽 一切都好嗎
Hey, Mom. Everything all right?
當然 我就是想過來看看
Of course. I just felt like making a stop
社區大學的神圣殿堂
by the hallowed halls of community college.
那些封條是怎么回事
What's with the police tape?
有一些兄弟會的人想把
Oh, some frat guys decided
院長的車開到火人節去
to drive the dean's office to Burning Man.
好吧 反正
Okay. Well, anyhoo,
既然來都來了
since we're here,
在你棄掉歷史課之前
before you drop that history class,
能不能把我以前的論文交上去呢
could you possibly turn in an old paper of mine?
我想看看別人的評分
I would love to get a second opinion on it.
當然
Sure,
但是你知道你對我提了一個很奇怪的要求
but you know you just did something weird
而我一個問題都沒多問吧
and I didn't ask a single follow-up question?
對
Yeah.
你欠我一次這樣的請求
You owe me one of those.
你是怎么把以前的論文導進U盤里的
How'd you even get an old paper on a thumb drive?
很容易...
It was easy.
吧
Ish.
那篇久遠的論文是老舊的格式
The old paper was on an old format,
但是把幾臺老機器連接起來
but it was a simple matter
就能很容易地得到
of stringing a couple of old machines together
我需要的東西了
to get what I needed.
好了
All right.
我一直因為完美主義
Yes, I have been accused of having
飽受詬病
a little problem with perfectionism...
? 它在運作 ?
♪ It's working ♪
但是我對于不公也有意見
...but I also have a little problem with injustice,
就像某位美國總統
much as a certain U.S. President had a little problem
對歐洲帝國主義的看法一樣 棒
with European Imperialism. Yes!
當然當一個男人這么做的時候 那是教義
Of course when a man does it, it becomes a doctrine.
而當一個女人這樣做
and when a woman does it,
她就是歇斯底里
she's hysterical.
我希望你們喜歡數"烏鴉"
I hope you guys like counting "crows".
"一只烏鴉"[第三方契約]
Es-crows, that is.
這已經成了熟悉的聲音
It had become a familiar sound --
我的18個投入的學生笑聲合一
my 18 devoted students laughing as one.
只是這次有些不對勁
Only something was different this time.
聽起來像是17個
It sounded like 17.
難道中間有人動搖了
Could it be that I had a wobbler in my midst?
果然 佩奇·史蒂文斯
Sure enough, Paige Stevens
正在翻閱課程目錄
was going through the course catalog.
要是她走了 我的課程就不足最小人數
If I lost her, I'd be below my minimum
這門課就會被停
and lose the class.
為了其他17個追夢者
For the sake of those 17 dreamers,
我別無選擇 只能施展我的鄧菲魅力
I had no choice but to unleash the Dunphy charm.
-佩奇·史蒂文斯 -到
- Paige Stevens. - Present.
我們已經點過名了 你表現得很好
Oh, we already did that part, and you nailed it.
我昨天晚上讀了你的文章
I read your essay last night.
你私下跟誰一起學習了
Whom did you study privately with?
-不好意思你說什么 -別裝了 佩奇
- I'm sorry? - Come, now, Paige.
你的見解 你的遣詞造句
Your insight, your grasp of the vernacular.
是弗里蒙特嗎
W-Was it Freemont?
還是某一位歐洲人
Or perhaps one of the Europeans?
沙爾芬貝格
Scharfenbrugen?
-不是 -當然不
- No. - Oh, of course not.
他過著隱居的生活 多年沒有收學生了
He lives as a recluse. He hasn't taken students in years.
我是想表達
I'm simply saying
你天生的直覺
that your raw instincts
可能是1994年允許傭金分割以來
may be the best thing to happen to real estate
房地產界的最強福音
since the allowing of split commissions in 1994.
你不是跟我們說那是
Didn't you tell us it was --
我們就不能有一會兒
Can we for one moment
能不是你的瑟奇個人秀嗎
have a break from the Serge show?!
向我保證幾年后
Just promise me that in a few short years
當你成為下一個弗萊德·鄧納姆時
when you become the next Fred Dunham,
你會回來看我們
that you'll come visit us?
你真的覺得
Do you really think...
我不是覺得
I don't think.
我知道會
I know.
就是那兒 一點奉承
From there, it was a bit of flattery,
一絲鼓勵
a dash of encouragement,
佩奇就回心轉意了
and Paige was turned.
讓我把我們的明星學員
So, if I could paraphrase
剛才指出的點改述一下
what our star pupil just pointed out,
有時候問題只是要
sometimes it's just a matter
找到愿意買復式住宅的復式傻子
of finding the "Dupe" in "Duplex."
那個聲音又出現了
And there it was again,
那動聽的音樂
that sweet music --
18個人的歡笑聲
18 people laughing.
所有人下周再見
I'll see you all next week.
肯定的
Definitely.
還有 我會在家辦公
Oh, and I am holding office hours at my house,
歡迎你們隨時來訪
so feel free to come by any time.
沒問題
Oh, cool.
你...
Oh, you --
佩奇
Uh, Paige.
"佩奇·鄧菲夫人"
"Mrs. Paige Dunphy"?
詛咒啊
Curses.
我鼓勵地太過了
I'd over-wooed my wobbler.
我們今晚還一起吃晚餐嗎
Are we still on for dinner tonight?
當然 我大概能在我外公的俱樂部
Yeah, I can probably get us in
弄到打烊前用餐的座位名額
to the late seating at my grandpa's country club.
你能等到六點半嗎
Can you hold off 'ti:30?
其實 我在想
Actually, I thought
也許我可以去你家給你做飯吃
maybe I could come over and cook for you.
太棒了
Awesome.
這不是我最喜歡的班級爸爸嗎
Hey, there's my favorite class dad!
你好啊
Oh, hey. Hey.
幫我系下圍裙 好嗎
Tie my apron, will you?
我的榮幸
My pleasure.
不 不是我的榮幸[舒服] 當然不是
Uh, not my -- not my pleasure, of course.
這聽起來太奇怪了
That sounds weird,
而我不是奇怪的人
and I'm not a weird man.
米奇和小卡攪亂了我的心
Mitch and Cam got in my head.
我本來和那個有趣媽媽有一段完全無害的關系
I'd had a perfectly innocent relationship with the fun mom,
結果被他們弄得我老有負罪感
but then they got me feeling all guilty.
突然間我在學校提到的每件事
Suddenly I couldn't mention one thing in that school
聽起來都像是雙關語
without it sounding like a double entendre.
"睡覺"時間
Nap time?
樂趣"地帶"
Fun zone?
盒裝[陰部]果汁
Juice box...
我有鮮嫩多汁的番茄呢
I got some nice tomatoes.
好
Oh, yep.
-你是不是弄灑了什么 -沒有
- Did you spill something? - Huh? No.
我只是在很用心地做披薩
I'm just working hard on this pizza.
我想我得把這個取下來
Guess I ought to take this off.
天啊 沒了戒指感覺像裸體了一樣
Boy, feels naked without it.
你有過這種感覺嗎 像裸體了一樣
You ever feel that way? Naked?
我真心想相信喬有戴著他的眼罩
I really wanted to trust that Joe was wearing his eye patch,
但是自從在垃圾箱里發現眼罩之后
but after finding it in the garbage,
我必須得來確認
I had to make sure.
我不想讓他把視力給毀了
I didn't want him to mess up his vision.
我認為在這個國家 視力是一個很重要的問題
I think it's a big problem in this country.
我所到之處 總有瞇著眼看的男人
Everywhere I look, there are men with googily eyes.
我們來自拍吧
Let's take a selfie
是給學校期刊拍的
for the school newsletter, so...
所以顯出那對藍眼睛來
Flash those baby blues.
你給我的烤箱[子宮]預熱了嗎
Did you preheat my oven?
我不是故意的
Not on purpose.
你剛才反應可真不小啊
Well, that was quite a little snitfit back there.
你是想要讓我出丑 還是怎么了
Were you trying to embarrass me, or...?
還能有讓你更出丑的事嗎
Mm, is that even possible?
要贏過在餐廳唱歌
The singing in the restaurants,
或者按摩時為廣告的"試音"可不容易啊
your Herbal Essence audition during the massage?
你知道嗎 你才是應該羞愧的那個人
You know, you're the one who should be embarrassed.
我的確感到了羞愧 這不正是吵架的原因嗎
I am. Isn't that what we're fighting about?
看看你自己 你甚至不敢
Look at you. You can't even put on
在男士換衣間里
your boxer-briefs in a men's locker room
不用遮羞毛巾小短裙就穿上四角褲
without your little terrycloth shame skirt.
這叫做有涵養 小卡
It's called modesty, Cam.
你能把聲音放小點兒嗎
Can you please just keep your voice down?
好吧 你知道嗎 這都是
Yeah, yeah. You know what? Well, it's all
同樣的事
part of the same thing.
你知道嗎 我一點都不尷尬
You know, I'm not embarrassing.
你就是個無論做什么都會尷尬的人
You're the one that's just embarrassed by everything.
簡直是神經病啊
That is crazy --
-感覺這一撞很值得呢 -我很好
- This seems worth it. - I'm fine.
不 你不好 而這影響了我們所有人
No, you're not, and it's affecting all of us.
你總是讓我和莉莉閉嘴
You're constantly shushing Lily and me,
責罵我們就因為我們活得大聲
scolding us just for living out loud.
我們就不能晚點再說這件事嗎
Can we please have this conversation later?
不 不能 因為我會忙著
No, we can't, because I'll be busy
在父親節目中演出
performing in Fathers' Follies --
另一件因為你太扭捏而不敢做的事
something else you're too self-conscious to do.
你錯過了生活 米奇爾
You're missing out on life, Mitchell.
你得不再那么拘束自己
You need to take off your shackles.
讓人們看見
Let people see
你是誰
who you are.
我受夠了 閃躲的眼神 那些謊言
I've had enough -- the wandering eye, the lies.
我為什么這么緊張 我什么都沒做錯
Why was I so nervous? I had done nothing wrong.
好吧 我確實有開一些無害的郵件玩笑
Sure, I engaged in some friendly e-mail banter.
我想我意識到了藍色衣服能襯托我的藍眼珠
I guess I realized blue shirts make my eyes sparkle.
披薩派對開始前 也許還在停車場
Might have done a few push-ups in the parking lot
做了幾個俯臥撐 但那是給所有人看的
before the pizza party, but that's for everybody.
他就是把我當傻瓜
He's trying to make a fool of me.
索尼婭 我得掛了
Sonia, I have to go.
你一整天都到哪里去了
Where have you been all day?
我明白你在暗示什么了 好吧
I see what you're implying. Fine.
她的名字是勞拉 她對我來說什么都不是
Her name is Laura, she means nothing to me,
我把婚戒取掉的唯一原因
and the only reason my wedding ring is off
是我怕戒指丟在她的"面團"里
is 'cause I was afraid I would lose it in her dough.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你到底在說什么
What the hell are you talking about?
幾封郵件 完全無害的小玩笑罷了
Couple of e-mails. Harmless stuff.
"把車停在秋千那 好幫你把東西拿進來"
"Park by the swings so I can help you carry stuff in."
你就在擔心這些啊
These are what you're worrying about?
這些什么都不是啊
There's nothing there.
是嗎 米奇和小卡在暗示
Yeah, Mitch and Cam were implying
我跟她之間有不尋常的事情
there was something weird going on.
怎么可能嘛
That's crazy.
她才35歲 還貌美如花
She's, like, 35 and gorgeous.
就是啊
Exactly.
不過 我想你念郵件時
Although, I don't think you read that e-mail
沒念出它本身的語氣
the only way it could have been read.
其實是這種語氣
I mean, it could've gone,
"把車停在秋千那
"Park by the swings
好幫你把東西拿"進"來"
so I can help you carry stuff in."
聽上去她知道你背不好
Sounds like she knows about your bad back.
杰 小撩一下無傷大雅
Jay, there's no harm in a little flirting,
-特別是你 -此話怎講
- especially you. - What is that supposed to mean?
你是個好人 你體內自帶警報系統
You're a good man. You have, like, a built-in alarm system.
不會讓你行差踏錯
It keeps you in the right path.
那你在學校為什么那樣瞪我
Then why did you shoot me that look at school?
我那是在瞪喬
It was meant for Joe.
我擔心他沒有你那種強烈的道德心
I worry that he doesn't have your strong conscience.
我害怕他遺傳了我家的基因
I worry that he has my family genes
我們說謊都不打草稿
where we can lie and lie and lie and lie
而且不會有絲毫愧疚
without feeling one ounce of guilt.
但你平時沒對我說謊吧
Y-You don't lie to me, though, do you?
從沒有過
Never.
他來了 我猜他一定會進來
Here he is now. I'll bet he comes in here
為自己說謊道歉
and apologizes for lying.
前提是他遺傳了你們家的正直基因
Yeah, if he's like one from your family.
但如果他進來 像個沒事人一樣
But if he walks in here all easy-breezy
假裝自己沒做錯過任何事
pretending that he didn't do anything wrong,
那他就是百分百拉米雷茲家的人
he's 100% Ramirez,
或者這也不是我們真正的姓
or whatever our real name is.
兒子
Hey, buddy.
對不起 行了嗎
I'm sorry, okay?!
戴眼罩的事我說謊了
I lied about wearing my eye patch,
那還只是一系列謊言的開始
and that's only the beginning!
我自行車怎么壞的 我說謊了
I lied about how my bike broke.
我從沒遛過斯黛拉
I never walk Stella.
我把她拴在跑步機上
I tie her to the treadmill.
我之前放在枕頭底下的三顆掉牙
The last three teeth I put under my pillow
其實都是薄荷糖
were Tic-Tacs.
我是個無可救藥的男孩
I'm a terrible boy.
太好了
Oh, good.
他跟你一樣軟弱
He's weak like you.
謝謝你 蒂凡尼的爸爸
Thank you, Tiffany's dad!
接下來 請掌聲歡迎
And now, please put your hands together
莉莉 哈珀 扎克和丹妮爾的爸爸們
for Lily, Harper, Zack, and Danielle's dads --
"蜜蜂之膝[生意]"組合
The Bees Knees!
爸爸加油
Go, Dad! Woot, woot!
我是觀眾席里唯一的爸爸
I was the only dad in the audience.
臺下坐著的都是女性和孩子 就我一個男人
It was just me and a bunch of women and children.
我感覺自己就像硬擠上救生艇的懦夫
I felt like a coward on a life boat.
小卡說得對 我錯過了很多
I mean, Cam was right -- I-I was missing out.
鮑勃 幫我個小忙
Hey, Bob. A quick favor to ask.
如果哈珀不介意
If you don't think Harper would mind,
你能不能把蜜蜂表演服給我穿一下
do you think maybe I could wear the bee costume?
拿去吧 反正我之后還有表演
Take it. I'm in the show later anyways,
在"感恩之父"組合里唱低音部
playing bass with the Grateful Dads.
那就給我吧
Then good, yeah.
天啊 我真為你感到驕傲
Oh, my God. I'm so proud of you!
謝謝 謝謝各位
Thank you. Thank you!
現在請大家安靜片刻
And now we'd like to take a moment
我們一起緬懷親愛的食堂阿姨
to remember our beloved lunch lady,
佩妮·米勒太太
Mrs. Penny Miller.
老天
Oh, my gosh.
你居然這么做了
I can't believe you did that!
-太棒了 -哎呀別夸了
- That was amazing! - Oh, stop it.
不
No!
天啊
Oh, God.
我們還沒吸取手套的教訓嗎
Did we learn nothing from the gloves?!
抱歉 抱歉 抱歉 我來 我來
Sorry, sorry, sorry. I got it. I got it.
我來弄 我來處理
I got it. I got it. I got it.
頭盤
For starters,
是用我祖母配方做的意大利餃子
my grandmother's ravioli.
看起來很好吃
It looks amazing.
我房間里存著一些紅酒 以備不時之需
I've been saving some occasion wine in my room.
盒子上的葡萄特性一欄寫著"媽媽咪呀"
The grape character on the box is saying "Mamma Mia!"
所以應該跟意大利料理很搭
so it should go well with Italian.
教授 您好
Hello, Professor.
我...
I, uh...
看來你接受了我提議的"門戶開放政策"
I see you took me up on that open-door policy I mentioned.
我不是來問你學習的事
Oh, I'm not here for office hours.
-這是個約會 -毫不意外
- This is a date. - Of course.
我聽說披頭士樂隊的保羅·麥卡尼當紅時
I've heard things like this happened to Paul McCartney
也遇到過這種事
at the height of his Beatles fame.
典型的《致命誘惑》套路
It was a classic fatal-attraction situation.
我必須做兩件事
I had to do two things.
第一 撐過接下來的十分鐘
One -- get through the next 10 minutes
拖到棄我課的截止時間過了為止
'til the deadline to drop my class had passed
方法是用詼諧的玩笑轉移她的注意力
by distracting her with light banter
和享用她做的托斯卡納料理 第二
and enjoying her Tuscan cooking, and, two --
確認下她有沒有暴打克萊爾并把她綁了起來
check to see if she had beaten and restrained Claire.
我會不會用力過猛了
I'm not coming on too strongly,
穿這條裙子來約會
am I, with this dress?
不會
Oh. No.
很可愛
Lovely.
我對自己的烹飪很沒自信
I'm really nervous about my cooking.
如果一個男人沒有吃光
If a guy doesn't eat every bite
我祖母的意大利餃子
of my grandma's ravioli,
我會發瘋
I go nuts.
我們當然
Well, we certainly...
不希望有這種事發生
don't want that to happen,
對吧
do we?
話說
Now, uh...
你是哪里人
where are you from?
老家在哪里
Originally.
我猜是意大利
I would say Italy,
但你沒有口音
but there's no accent,
所以你肯定不是
so, obviously, that's not the case.
盧克
Luke.
盧克 我關于門羅主義那篇論文有消息了嗎
Luke, any word on my Monroe Doctrine paper?
其實 我決定
Oh, actually, I decided
不棄那門課了
not to drop that class,
所以把論文交上去好像不太好
so it didn't feel right turning it in.
不過發生了有趣的事
But something funny did happen.
我在電腦上打開了你寫的論文
I had your paper open on my computer.
佩奇看到了 以為是我寫的
Paige saw it and thought it was mine.
她做了一些很棒的改動
She made some really good changes.
-改動 -是啊
- Changes? - Yeah, well,
她在幾個地方直接切入正題
she cut to the chase in a few places,
把結尾部分做了精簡
cleaned up the ending.
她其實是歷史專業的學生呢
She's a history major, you know.
-懂了 -媽 我...
- Get it. - Mom, I'm...
跟人家還在晚餐約會中呢
kind of in the middle of a dinner date.
是嗎 如果你繼續約會
Are you? By now you might be
你們說不定電影已經看一半 或者在玩桌游了
in the middle of a movie or a board game.
畢竟我們都知道她這人有多愛做改變
We all know how obsessed she is with changing things.
去把論文給我拿來 盧克
Go get the paper, Luke.
太好了 你沒事
Oh, good, you're okay.
誰說老娘沒事了
I'm not that okay.
我對這佩奇可不太感冒
I'm not a fan of this Paige.
-她挺狗膽包天 -所以你知道了
- She's got some nerve. - So you're aware.
我當然知道 我清楚知道她毫不介意
Oh, I'm aware. I'm aware that she has no problem
把自己的賤爪伸向
putting her grubby, little paws all over
不屬于她的事物上
something that doesn't belong to her.
-我看出你很不爽 -是的
- I can see you're upset. - I am.
我不爽的原因是因為
I'm upset because I basically took
我把史上最無聊的東西拿來并弄得有趣
the most boring thing in history and made it interesting.
她大搖大擺走過來就當成自己的東西拿走
She thinks she can just come in here and just make it hers.
-做夢吧 -我有點被傷到
- No. - Feels a little hurtful,
但她是我的學生 這事對我影響巨大
but she is my student, and I have a lot at stake here,
能求你把這件事留給我自己處理嗎
so can I please just handle this myself?
你沒吃到意大利餃也不算虧
You didn't miss much with the ravioli.
真正的好戲是我的海鱸魚
The showstopper is my branzino.
聞起來好香啊
It smells great.
我們家平常沒機會吃到魚
We don't get to have fish around here.
我爸超討厭吃魚
My dad hates it.
這是我們的家傳食譜
Well, this one's a family recipe,
如果你不愛吃 我可能就得拋棄你了
so if you don't like it, I'll pretty much have to drop you.
既然如此
Well...
那我們還是
let's not have
不要再說
any of that
任何瘋話了
crazy...talk.
離時限還有2分鐘
Two minutes to deadline.
我不能讓她棄了我的課
I couldn't let her drop my class!
現在
Now
繼續
...back...
說你是從哪里來的
... to where you're from.
加州恩西諾
Encino.
靠
Damn it.
媽 別生她氣 她只是...
Mom, don't be mad at her. She was just --
沒 她真的改良了許多
No, she made it better.
我寫這句的時候腦子里想什么呢
What was I thinking with this sentence?
"受人敬仰的大律師的論點
"The esteemed barrister's argument was as layered
充滿層次 仿佛他的晚宴后馬褲一般"
as the cuffs on his after-dinner breeches"?
這是我第三次提到馬褲了
That is the third time I mentioned breeches.
我當年是在鬧哪樣啊
What was I going through?
-我可以走了嗎 -可以
- Can I go now? - Yeah.
等等 寶貝
Oh, wait, honey.
我覺得這姑娘挺好
I like this girl for you.
她值得你請她喝比盒裝紅酒更好的酒
She deserves better than boxed wine.
海莉有瓶好酒藏在床底下了
Haley keeps a nice bottle under her bed.
你好像很喜歡吃這道菜
You really seemed to like that.
-是的 -我可以再去做一份
- Oh, yeah. - I could make another one,
但需要花一點時間
but it would take a while.
我看看 現在是7點了
Let's see. It's 7:00 now --
謝天謝地啊
Oh, thank God.
佩奇 我們得聊聊
Paige, we have to talk.
我可能無意間發出了讓你誤會的信號
I-I may have sent some signals I didn't mean to send.
盡管如此 你的一些舉動
Nonetheless, some of your behavior
老實說 稍微有點不太合適
has been a little inappropriate, frankly,
而且也對我妻子有點不敬
kind of disrespectful to my wife.
等等 別急 別說下去
Oh, wait, hang on. Hang on.
這件事我其實改變心意了
I changed my mind about that.
我不生你氣
I am not mad at you.
你所做的事只不過是對
All you did was take an interest in something
我25年前就該丟棄的一件事物起了興趣
that I should have dropped 25 years ago.
-克萊爾 -我能跑題一下嗎
- Um, Claire. - And can I say something else?
我十分支持你們交往
I'm all in favor of this relationship.
-克萊爾 -我不想話說太早帶來壞運
- Claire? - I don't want to jinx it,
但我覺得你可能真的是他的真命天女
but I think you could be exactly what he needs.
我懂 雖然他看起來像個男人
I know, he may look like a man,
但老實說 在很多方面
but, honestly, in a lot of ways,
他還只是個小男孩
he's still just a little boy.
"房"里的事只能用一團亂來形容
Complete mess in the bedroom.
不過我可以給你個小秘訣
Although, here's a tip for you.
如果你能"駕馭"在他之上 他表現會變好
He actually does respond well if you stay on top of him.
-所以你不介意我跟... -完全不介意
- So, you're okay with... - Absolutely.
如同某位美國早年前總統說過的
As a certain U.S. President once said,
"讓感覺良好的年代開始吧"
"Let the era of good feelings commence."
天啊 這真是我最開心的一天了
Oh, my God! This is the best day ever!
原來佩奇給我做晚餐
So, it turns out Paige was only making dinner for me
純粹是因為想接近我爸
so she could get close to my dad.
抱歉了 小兄弟 但我警告過大家
I am sorry, buddy, but I did warn everyone
我強大的鄧菲魅力了
about the Dunphy charm.
另一件有趣的事情是
It's also a little interesting
佩奇的房產中介父親在她12歲時
that Paige's Realtor dad abandoned the family
-拋妻棄女跑了 -感覺沒關聯啊
- when she was 12. - Seems irrelevant.
他也對魔術有過涉獵
He also dabbled in magic.
感覺我們現在完全是在聊兩個不同的話題啊
Now we're just having two separate conversations.
你知道她前3任男友都是50歲以上人士嗎
Did you know her last three boyfriends were 50?
我勸你還是少花時間去讀
Maybe spend a little less time with your nose
你那些心理學的書 多花點時間變性感吧
in that psych book and a little more time being sexy.
等你寫完作業了才還給你
You will get this back when your homework is done.
喬 這是什么
Joe, what is this?
我朋友漢娜給我的紙條
Just the notes from my friend Hannah.
朋友嗎 我感覺可不是這么一回事
Friend? This doesn't sound to me like that.
這些字條很挑逗呢
This is very flirty.
讓我看看
Let me see that.
"親愛的喬 你想跟我分著吃水果軟糖卷嗎"
"Dear Joe, wanna share a half of my fruit roll-ups?"
這只是小孩子的童言童語嘛
This is just kids being kids.
好傻好天真
Don't be a fool.
"親愛的喬 你想跟我
"Dear Joe, wanna share a half
分著吃水果軟糖卷嗎"
of my fruit roll-ups?"
你這角度看確實不一樣
That's a different spin on it.
你這性感聲線以前都躲哪了
Where's that voice been?
念念這條
Done this one.
"下課時間一起跑來跑去好好玩啊"
"It was so fun running at recess."
"蘭迪的疹子真的好惡心啊"
"Randy's rash is really gross."
或許我們該上樓"談談"
Maybe we should go upstairs.
看你的電影吧 喬
Watch your movie, Joe.